# Cedric Nugteren

Curriculum Vitae



## Address: Hoogte Kadijk 155 1018BJ Amsterdam Netherlands

#### Contact:

+31 6 18193288 www.cedricnugteren.nl mail@cedricnugteren.nl

Year of birth: 1986

**Nationality:** Dutch

## Summary

I received my Bachelors (Electrical Engineering) and Masters (Embedded Systems) from Eindhoven University of Technology. In April 2014, I successfully defended my PhD thesis at the same university. During my PhD I gained experience through two internships: with the OpenCL compiler group of ARM in Cambridge (UK), and with the cuFFT team of NVIDIA in Santa Clara (CA). After my PhD, I started working as a GPU consultant at the SURFsara supercomputing centre.

My main expertise is GPU programming (CUDA/OpenCL). On top of this, I have also experience with compilers, HPC, processor architecture, and performance modelling. I am also interested in modern and elegant accelerator programming models, such as OpenMP 4.0, SyCL and Boost.Compute.

My passion is developing beautiful and performant C++11 codes, possibly accelerated by GPUs.

## Work experience

#### 05/2014 - Current GPU/Supercomputing consultant, SURFsara, Netherlands

I am a consultant for the Dutch supercomputing/HPC centre, specialised in accelerator programming (Xeon Phi, GPU). I have worked on codes from various scientific domains, including finite element methods, fluid dynamics, and quantum chemistry.

#### 01/2014 - 04/2014 Intern, NVIDIA Santa Clara, California

I worked for four months as a GPU programmer at the NVIDIA headquarters within the math libraries group, developing and performance tuning the CUDA Fast Fourier Transform library (cuFFT).

### 08/2012 - 12/2012 Research intern, ARM Cambridge, UK

During a 4-month HiPEAC internship I performed research within the Mali OpenCL compiler team. The result is a machine-code level mathematical performance model for the Mali low-power GPUs.

**11/2009 - 11/2010 Scientific Programmer,** *Eindhoven University of Technology,* Netherlands Within the Electronic Systems group, I worked full-time as a scientific programmer, which included research into processor architecture (GPUs, SIMD) targeted at image and video processing applications.

#### 10/2009 - 12/2014 Founder and owner of Kinento, Kinento, Netherlands

Kinento is a privately owned e-commerce company. Three PHP extensions to Magento were developed and maintained. From 2015 onwards, they are open-sourced and available for free on GitHub.

## **Education**

### 11/2010 - 04/2014 PhD, Eindhoven University of Technology, Netherlands

Under the supervision of prof. H. Corporaal, I performed research on GPUs. This covered most aspects of GPUs, including architecture, compilers, performance modelling, and programmability. This has led to two journal articles, a patent application, and several publications in international conferences and workshops. My PhD thesis is titled 'Improving the Programmability of GPU Architectures'.

08/2007 - 08/2009 MSc. in Embedded Systems, Eindhoven University of Technology, Netherlands

08/2004 - 08/2007 BSc. Electrical Engineering, Eindhoven University of Technology, Netherlands

## **Skills**

#### General

Highly motivated/driven, strong presenting/documenting skills, well organised, sociable, creative

#### Languages

Dutch (native speaker), English (very good), French (good), Spanish (basic)

#### **Computer proficiency**

Main languages: C, C++/C++11, CUDA, OpenCL, Ruby

Miscellaneous: CMake, Git

## Selected publications

#### In 2014

- → C. Nugteren, H. Corporaal. Bones: An Automatic Skeleton-Based C-to-CUDA Compiler for GPUs. *ACM TACO 11. 4. Article 35*, 2014.
- → C. Nugteren, G.J. van den Braak, H. Corporaal. A Study of the Potential of Locality-Aware Thread Scheduling for GPUs. *In MuCoCoS* '14. Springer, 2014.
- → C. Nugteren. Improving the Programmability of GPU Architectures. PhD-thesis, Eindhoven University of Technology. 2014.
- → C. Nugteren, G.J. van den Braak, H. Corporaal, H. Bal. A Detailed GPU Cache Model Based on Reuse Distance Theory. *In HPCA '14*. IEEE, 2014.

#### In 2013

- → C. Nugteren, R. Corvino, H. Corporaal. **Algorithmic Species Revisited: A Program Code Classification Based on Array References**. In *MuCoCoS '13*. IEEE, 2013.
- → C. Nugteren, P. Custers, H. Corporaal. Algorithmic Species: An Algorithm Classification of Affine Loop Nests for Parallel Programming. ACM TACO 9, 4, Article 40. 2013.

## In 2012

- → C. Nugteren, H. Corporaal. The Boat Hull Model: Enabling Performance Prediction for Parallel Computing Prior to Code Development. In CF '12. ACM, 2012.
- → C. Nugteren, H. Corporaal. Introducing 'Bones': A Parallelizing Source-to-Source Compiler Based on Algorithmic Skeletons. In *GPGPU-5*. ACM, 2012.

#### In 2011

→ C. Nugteren, G.J. v.d. Braak, H. Corporaal, B. Mesman. **High Performance Predictable Histogramming on GPUs**. In *GPGPU-4*. ACM, 2011.

#### Referees

- ✓ Henk Corporaal, PhD advisor at Eindhoven University of Technology
- Anton Lokhmotov, Internship supervisor at ARM
- ✓ Alex Fit-Florea, Teamleader at NVIDIA